Nate A. Miller 4060 Albion St., Apt. 205, Denver, CO 80216-4454 (970) 396-4249 • nmiller2379@gmail.com

QUALIFICATIONS SUMMARY

Knowledge of HTML, CSS, Javascript, Node.js. Excellent coaching, management and editing skills. Outstanding experience as an editor and reporter. Good grammar and Associated Press style skills. Strong knowledge of computer programs such as NewsEditPro IQue, Adobe Photoshop, Publicus Online Publishing System, QuarkXPress, Word, and WordPerfect.

WORK HISTORY

University of Denver, Denver, Colo.

Student. Present

Attending the University of Denver's full-stack web developer bootcamp, learning both front-end and back-end coding in challenging, faced-paced learning environment.

United Parcel Service, Denver, Colo.

Package Handler, 2019-Present

Sort packages to shipment destinations in fast-paced environment that requires concentration and physical fitness. Also work as a trainer for new package handlers as assigned by supervisor.

The Tribune, Greeley, Colo.

Editor, 2017-2018

Led a team of 25 to provide coverage of local and regional news across print and digital platforms every day. Responsible for a departmental operating budget and creating an implementing editorial strategy for the paper. Led editorial production for several niche publications. Coach and mentored front-line supervisors.

Local News Editor, 2013-2017

Coordinate local news coverage online and in print. Edit local news content daily. Supervise seven news reporters. Write police-related and other breaking news. Take photos as needed. Coach reporters, plan and execute daily local news coverage in coordination with editor's content strategy.

Assistant Local News Editor, 2007-2013

Helped coordinate weekend news coverage online and in print. Edit local news content daily. Covered politics and Legislature for a 22,000 circulation daily. Wrote in-depth enterprise stories, features and breaking political news. Took photos as needed. Supervising editor for Panorama special section. Also covered business beat from December, 2007 to December 2008.

Sports Editor, 2005-2007

Managed content and production for multiple editions of The Tribune sports section. Supervised seven staff members. Managed staff reorganization to facilitate expansion into new markets. Added new beats and special sections. Supervised online Tribune sports content. Edited and designed eight pages nightly on deadline. Coached writers. Planned and executed in-depth enterprise coverage.

Assistant Sports Editor, 2004-2005

Edited and designed nightly pages on deadline. Supervised six staff members. Assisted in

planning of sports coverage, including special sections and online. Also served as interim sports editor from August to September 2004 and in August 2005.

Reporter Intern/Stringer, 2002-2004

Regularly covered police beat, breaking news. Wrote stories ranging from high school football coverage to in-depth features about topics such as health care and special education, including general assignment enterprise and news-feature stories.

The Rocky Mountain News, Denver

Stringer, Summer 2003

Covered University of Northern Colorado angle of the Kobe Bryant rape allegations.

The Mirror, University of Northern Colorado

Editor in Chief, 2002-2003

Led editorial content and production for a 7,000-circulation tabloid, which published three times a week. Supervised 30 staff members. Managed editorial/opinion page. Coached writers and editors. Initiated an electronic page-proofing system that streamlined production, allowed copy editors to check all elements on pages and substantially reduced errors. Stepped up crime coverage with a police scanner, daily checks of police reports and regular calls to emergency services agencies. Also served as news editor from January 2001 to April 2002 and news reporter from October 2000 to April 2002.

Denver Daily News, Denver

Reporter Intern, Summer 2001

Regularly covered Denver City Council. Wrote stories about council meetings, kept current about citywide issues and wrote enterprise stories. Wrote general assignment stories as needed.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

University of Northern Colorado political science major, bachelor of arts, 2004 Edward Miller's Newsroom Leadership Group newspaper management conference, 2007 Swift Newspapers management training, 2006

Swift Newspapers management training basic course, 2006

Colorado Press Association workshops in layout and design, and copy editing and headline writing, 2005

University of Georgia Management Seminar for College Newspaper Editors, 2002 University of Northern Colorado Reporting Contemporary Issues, 2002

RECENT AWARDS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

Second place, special section, Colorado Press Association, 2009

Associated Press Sports Editors Top 10 daily section, 2008

Associated Press Sports Editors Top 10 Sunday section, 2007

Associated Press Sports Editors Top 10 special section, 2006

The Tribune employee of the month, August 2004

First place, investigative writing, Wyoming Press Association Collegiate Competition, 2002